>> Good afternoon everybody.
>> 大家下午好
Welcome to session 220,
欢迎参加 220 主题会议
customize loading in WKWebView.
WKWebView 中的自定义加载
My name is Brady Eidson.
我是 Brady Eidson
I'm a software engineer on this
Apple 团队的
[inaudible] teams at Apple.
一名软件工程师
A little later I'll be joined up
稍后我的同事
here with my colleague, Alex
Alex Christensen 会和我一起
Christensen.
向大家介绍
Let's just start out with a
现在我想问一个
quick question.
很简短的问题
How many of you integrate web
在座有多少人会
content into your applications?
把网页内容集成到自己的手机应用里
You're probably all in the right
今天大家可能都
room.
来对了
Now a follow up.
接下来的问题是
How many of you have used
在座各位有多少人使用过
WKWebView to integrate that web
WKWebView 来集成网页
content?
内容呢
Fewer hands came up.
举手的人少了
Still a lot of you though.
不过还是蛮多的
So I'm very excited to talk
我的内心非常激动 想和大家
about some great new APIs in
聊一聊 WKWebView 里一些
WKWebView that will help all of
精彩 全新的 API 所有正在使用
you who are already using
WKWebView 的人  将会由此而完成一些
WKWebView do some cool new
炫酷新奇的事情  我们还希望能够
things and hopefully adopt --
帮助在座的其他人
help the rest of you to adopt
接受并使用
WKWebView.
WKWebView
Apple is a big believer in web
Apple 是网络技术的
technologies.
忠实信徒
We know how important they are
我们知道网络技术对我们的开发者
to our developers, our users,
我们的用户以及你们的用户而言
and your users.
有多么重要
We have a handful of different
我们拥有许多不同的技术
technologies you can use to
你可以通过它们
integrate web content in your
把网页内容集成到你的
application.
App 里
Today's talk is primarily about
今天的主要介绍内容是
WKWebView but I do briefly want
WKWebView 但我想简单地
to mention a different one which
谈谈另一个内容 那就是
is Safari View Controller.
Safari View Controller
If you need an in app web
如果你需要一种 App 内网页
browsing experience, Safari View
浏览体验 那么到目前为止
Controller is, by far, the
Safari View Controller 是
preferred way for you to go.
你的最佳选择
Using just a few lines of code,
你只需使用几行代码
you can integrate a powerful
就可以把强大的
secure web browser into your
安全网页浏览器集成到
app.
你的 App 当中
You don't even need to worry
你甚至无需担心
about adding the UI.
增添用户界面的问题
But underneath that UI is web
然而在用户界面之下 就是
content.
网页内容
And many of you have much deeper
在座许多人会有更高层次的需求
needs than a straight forward
而不是通过平淡无奇的
web browsing experience can
网页浏览体验
fulfill.
就能满足
You need customization of the
你们需要自定义
behavior of the loading of the
网页内容的加载行为
web content of how it renders,
它的渲染方式
of how it interacts with your
以及它如何与你的本地用户界面
native UI.
进行交互
In fact, many of you might be
事实上 很多人可能是
integrating the web content into
采用了某种方式
your native UI in such a way
把网页内容集成到你的本地用户界面里
that it's not even obvious
以致于你根本看不出
you're using web content at all.
是在使用网页内容
If this is you, then WKWebView
如果你是这种人 那么
is, by far, the preferred way to
目前为止 WKWebView 将是
go.
你的最佳选择
Now I want to briefly talk about
现在我想要简单说说
WKWebView's architecture.
WKWebView 的架构
When you integrate web content
当你使用 WKWebView
into your application using
把网页集成到 App 当中时
WKWebView, you are inviting the
实际上你是在向 App 里引入
entire web platform into your
整个网页平台
application with all of its
包括它的所有功能
power, all of its flexibility
所有的灵活性  以及
but also all of its complexity.
所有的复杂性
So WKWebView isolates your
所以说  WKWebView 用我们了解到的
application from this complexity
最好的办法  把你的 App 和这种复杂性
as best we know how.
隔离开来
It does this using process
它用进程隔离来完成
isolation.
这项操作
We load the web content and
我们加载网页内容
render it and execute
对它进行渲染  并执行
JavaScript, that type of stuff,
JavaScript 这类东西
in a separate process from your
它和你的 App 进程
application's process.
各自运行 互不重叠
This gives us some fantastic
这给我们在安全性方面
security benefits.
带来了一些极大的好处
We can protect your application
我们可以保护你的 App
from potentially malicious web
免受潜在恶意网页内容的
content.
损害
In fact, different bits of web
事实上 网页内容的不同部分
content can each run in their
可以在各自的网页进程中
own web process.
独立运行
So we can protect your trusted
因此 我们可以保护你的可信网页
web content from other
免遭其他潜在
potentially malicious web
恶意网页的
content.
攻击
This also opens up some great
这也带来了一些巨大的
performance benefits.
性能优势
Web content can be run
因为有安全保障
concurrently with your
网页内容就可以
application because of the
与你的 App 同时运行
security, we can enable the
我们可以启用高级的
advanced JavaScript Just-In-Time
JavaScript Just-In-Time
compiler.
编译器
But because all this is
但是 由于所有这些都是
happening in a separate process,
在一个独立进程中展开
the normal steps you would take
因此 你在配置流程时
to configure your process don't
采用的常规步骤
apply to the web content.
并不适用于网页内容
We need explicit APIs to
我们需要显式 API 与
interact with the web content.
网页内容进行交互
And every since we introduced
自从我们推出
WKWebView, we've been gathering
WKWebView 就一直在收集
feedback from developers of all
各式各样的开发者
types working on all sorts of
关于各种 App 开发的
applications.
反馈信息
And we've compiled a list of a
我们已经整理出一份清单
top three that we're going to
上面有我们今天将介绍的
introduce today.
三项最重要内容
And we think that these three
我们认为这三个新机制
new mechanisms will unlock some
将能充分发挥
pretty powerful capabilities
你们一直以来要求的
that you guys have been asking
极为强大的
for.
功能
So first we're going to
我们首先要介绍的是
introduce a way to manage
如何管理对于 WKWebView
cookies visible to a WKWebView.
可见的 Cookie
We're going to introduce a
我们还将介绍一种
fantastic mechanism for
非常棒的机制
filtering unwanted content from
它可以从你的 WebView 里过滤
your WebView.
不需要的内容
And finally, a way for you to
最后 给大家介绍一种
provide custom resources to web
能为网页内容提供自定义资源的方法
content no matter where you have
这样的话  无论你从哪里获得
the data for those custom
这些自定义资源的数据
resources.
都能派上用场
Wherever -- no matter where it
无论数据
comes from.
来自哪里
So first managing cookies.
那么 首先来说说 Cookie 管理
We actually know that a lot of
事实上 我们知道有许多
the developers dipping their
初次涉入 WKWebView
toes in the waters of WKWebView
这个领域的开发人员
are pretty new to the web
对网络平台
platform.
很不熟悉
So I briefly want to go over
所以我想简略介绍一下
what is a cookie?
什么是 Cookie
When a webpage is rendered in a
当某个网页在浏览器引擎中
browser engine, a lot of sub
进行渲染时 会出现
resources come up.
很多子资源
Images, JavaScript files, style
如图片 JavaScript 文件
sheets, things like that.
样式表  诸如此类
For each sub resource, we need
针对每一种子资源 我们都需要
to make a request to the server.
向服务器发出请求
The server needs to respond with
服务器需要响应
the data of the resource itself
资源本身的数据  以及
and some meta data about the
与该资源有关的一些
resource.
元数据
And both the requests and the
这些请求和响应里
responses include little bits of
都包含一小段数据
data called cookies.
称为 Cookie
The server will respond with a
服务器将使用浏览器所记忆
cookie which the browser
的 Cookie 进行响应
remembers and can send back out
并且能够在将来的请求中
to the server in future
将其发送回
requests.
服务器
This helps track a user's
这有助于追踪用户
session when using a web
在使用网络 App 时的
application.
会话
Things like their log in
这就像是他们登录时的
credentials.
凭据
Their log in state, a log in
他们的登录状态
token.
一种登录令牌
Or if it's a shopping
或者 如果是一个购物 App
application, perhaps, the state
它可能会记录
of their shopping cart and
用户购物车的状态和
what's in it.
其中的商品
When you're integrating web
当你把网页内容集成
content into your native
到本地 App 时
application, you often need to
你经常需要操纵
manipulate these bits of data.
这些小片段数据
You might know things ahead of
你需要提前知道
time to help prompt prime the
一些信息 这样有助于
WebView.
提示 WebView 做好准备
To make the experience smoother.
让体验变得更为流畅
You might need to do something
你可能需要执行某项操作
like add a log out button where
例如添加“注销”按钮
you could just delete the
这样你可以直接删除
session cookie or the cookie
会话的 Cookie  或者是
representing the user's session
代表用户登录会话
log in.
的 Cookie
There's also other -- another
为什么你可能会需要
type of why you need -- might
管理 Cookie
need to manage cookies which is
这个问题  还有另一方面的原因
the opposite of helping the
它与辅助会话进程
session along.
正好相反
You might need to protect the
你也许需要对用户进行保护
user from having a session
不让他们的会话
tracked for certain types of
被某些类型的 App 或者是某些用户
applications and perhaps,
进行追踪
certain types of users this is
近期以来
becoming more and more important
这个问题
to be aware of these days.
越来越引起人们的重视
So whatever your reason is to
因此 无论你出于何种原因
manipulate the cookies visible
要操纵某个 WKWebView 可见的
to a WKWebView, the new API,
Cookie  这个全新的 API
WKHTTPCookieStore, will do what
WKHTTPCookieStore 它将会满足
you need it to do.
你的相关需求
Using the HTTPCookieStore, you
使用 HTTPCookieStore 你就
can add and remove individual
可以添加和移除
cookies visible to a WebView.
WebView 可见的个人 Cookie 记录
Pretty straight forward.
非常直观明了
You can also get a list of all
你也能够获取一份列表
of the cookies visible in the
列出 WebView 里可见的
WebView.
所有 Cookie
You know if you're a veteran
如果你是一名经验丰富的
WKWebView user, you might have
WKWebView 用户 你可能已经
used JavaScript to get the
使用 JavaScript 获取过
cookies visible to the current
某个 WebView 在当前展示的文档
document displayed in a WebView
可见的 Cookie
but when you do that, you didn't
可是当你这样操作时 你并不能
get at the http only cookies
控制应该对 JavaScript
that are supposed to be hidden
进行隐藏  属性为
from JavaScript.
HttpOnly 的 Cookie
Now that is possible.
但现在就可以办到了
And then finally it adds a
最后 它为大家增添了
mechanism for you to observe
一种机制 可用于观察
changes to the cookie store.
Cookie 存储的变化
While you might be specifically
虽然你可能会特意
adding or removing cookies from
从 Cookie 存储里添加或移除 Cookie
the cookie store, any resource
但是  任何发送给服务器
requests that goes to a server
并返回的资源请求
and comes back could also add
都可以在存储里添加新的 Cookie
new cookies to the store or
或者是在页面执行的JavaScript
JavaScript executed in a page
也可以添加
could add new cookies.
新的 Cookie
And you can now observe those
现在你可以观察到这些
changes.
变化
So you can get to a specific
所以说 你可以通过 WKWebView Cookie 的
WKWebView cookie's store through
网址数据库
its website data store.
进入它某个具体的存储库
This is already a property
这已经是 WebView
that's exposed on a WebView's
配置中展现的一种
configuration.
属性
And now the website data store
目前来看  网址数据库
itself has a new property to get
自身已经拥有一种连接
to the cookie store.
Cookie 存储库的新属性
To add a cookie, you use the
你如果要添加 Cookie 就使用
already established HTTPCookie
已经设计好的 HTTPCookie API
API to construct the cookie
来构建自己想要放入
object you'd like to put in the
数据库的
data store.
Cookie 对象
The specifics of this are up to
这些具体细节取决于
you and the web service you are
你自己 以及你正在交互的
interacting with but once you
网络服务 不过  一旦你
have the cookie all set and
设置好 Cookie
ready to go, you'll call set
并且准备运行 你将从
cookie on the cookie store with
存有你自己 Cookie 的 Cookie 存储器里
your cookie.
调用 Set-Cookie
Now you'll notice there's your
现在你将看到  这里是
trailing closure here, a
你的尾随闭包
completion handler.
一个 Completion Handler
This process is asynchronous and
这个进程是不同步的
it needs to send out to all
它需要向外发送给
those processes involved in the
WKWebView 机制所包含
WKWebView mechanism that are
且与你的 App 相隔离的
isolated from your application.
所有进程
So you need to wait until WebKit
所以你需要等到 WebKit
decides it's all done and ready
来判定这一切都已
to go.
准备就绪
And you can be confident in your
你可以对你的
completion handler that any
Completion Handler 保持信心
request you load in the WebView
相信你在 WebView 里加载的
will have that cookie applied.
任何请求都会使用到这个 Cookie
If you need to manipulate the
如果你需要操纵
existing cookies, you can get at
现有的 Cookie 你可以获取到
the set of all cookies.
所有 Cookie 的集合
Again in your completion
再说一次 在你的 Completion Handler 中
handler, you'll have a set of
你将拥有一组 Cookie
the cookies and you can walk
你可以做些尝试
through and find the right one.
并找到那个最合适的
In this illustration, we're
在这个示例中  我们
going for logging the user out
要通过在 Cookie 里
by finding the log in cookie.
查找日志来注销用户
And then we'll call delete and
然后我们会调用删除
get rid of that cookie.
把那条 Cookie 处理掉
And again, in our completion
再次说明 在我们的 Compleition Handler 中
handler, we will know that any
我们将发现  今后出现在 WebView 里的
future requests in the WebView
任何请求都将会
will have that cookie removed.
移除这个 Cookie
And those are the basics of
这些是使用
managing cookies using
WKHTTPCookieStore 来管理 Cookie的
WKHTTPCookieStore.
基础知识
We'll see a little bit more
稍后我们将了解更多
about that later but I'd like to
与之相关的信息
move on to filtering unwanted
下面我想接着介绍 如何过滤
content.
不需要的内容
When you a load page in a
当你在 WebView HTML 文件里
WebView, an HTML document,
加载页面时
there's all those sub resources
所有那些子资源都会
that are loaded that I already
一同加载 我在前面提到过
mentioned.
这一点
And there's a number of reasons
有许许多多的原因
why you need to make on a
使得你需要
resource by resource basis a
以资源为基础
decision about whether or not to
来进行考虑 从而决定是否
load the resource or otherwise,
应该加载某个资源
change how the resource is
或者是改变资源加载的
loaded.
方式
A common case we hear from
我们从开发人员那里
developers is they're working on
经常听到的情况是
a browser targeted for schools,
他们正在创建一种浏览器  适用对象是学校
libraries, some other public
图书馆  以及其他公共场所
place where the content loaded
那些地方的浏览器
in the browser has to be family
加载的内容必须是
friendly.
老少皆宜的
So we need to filter out
因此我们需要过滤掉
everything is not family
所有不适合全家人使用的
friendly.
内容
In a similar vane, we've heard
从另一个类似的渠道 我们还从
from developers working on
设计企业局域网 App 的
corporate intranet applications
开发人员那里得知
that they have varying needs
他们在同一款 App 里
within the same app.
有不同的需求
One WebView might need to block
某一个 WebView 可能
all content that is not coming
需要拦截所有来自
from the corporate's network.
公司网络以外的内容
Another WebView might need to
另一个 WebView 可能需要
block all content coming from
拦截来自某些特定服务器的
certain specific servers.
所有内容
You can have each WebView setup
你可以对每个 WebView 进行设置
to do its own thing on a per sub
使它在每个子资源的基础上
resource basis.
完成自己的工作
And then there's insecure
此外还有不安全的
content.
内容
We can upgrade it to be as
我们可以对它进行升级  尽全力达到
secure as we possibly know how.
最佳安全度
This can help keep our user's
这样可以保证
data and their browsing activity
我们用户的数据、浏览行为
and our app's browsing activity
以及我们 App 的浏览行为
hidden from prying eyes.
免受他人窥探
So the new WKContentRuleList API
因此  全新的 WKContentRuleList API
will help you do all of these
将帮助你实现所有
things.
这些事情
Now if you're familiar with
好 如果你熟悉
Safari content blocking
Safari 的内容拦截扩展
extensions where you provide a
你可以在此提供一条
rule set to configure Safari to
用来配置 Safari  让它
block certain resources loads,
能够阻止某些资源的加载
the ContentRuleList has the same
ContentRuleList 与
syntax as those content blocker
那些内容拦截程序扩展的
extensions.
句法相同
With them, you can block
使用它们 你可以
specific resource loads by --
通过以下方式阻止
for example, matching the url of
特定的资源加载 例如
the resource to a regular
将资源的 URL 与正则表达式
expression.
进行匹配
You might be able to tell WebKit
你或许可以提前告诉 WebKit
ahead of time don't ever load
绝不要加载这样的
such urls.
URL
In some cases, if you block a
在某些情况下  如果你一古脑儿地拦截了
resource load all together, you
所有的资源  那么你就
can break the webpage in subtle,
可以用含蓄的方式
sometimes not so subtle ways.
有时可以用直白的方式
So there is a rule action where
因此有一个规则操作
you can tell WebKit to perform
你可以让 Webkit 执行加载
the load but make the resulting
但要让生成的内容
content invisible.
对用户不可见
And then finally we can upgrade
这样到最后我们就可以将
those insecure resource loads to
那些不安全的资源加载
be secure loads.
升级为安全的加载
This comes in two important
这有两种重要的
forms.
形式
One is any http plain text url
一种是你遇到的任何 HTTP
that is come across, you can
纯文本 URL  你可以把它
upgrade it to be an encrypted
升级为加密的
https url.
HTTP URL
And you can also block cookies
你也可以阻止 Cookie
from being sent out with certain
让它们无法和某些请求一起
requests.
向外发送
If the requests are to a
如果请求的资源具有
resource of a sensitive nature,
敏感内容 那么
you can prevent your user's data
你可以对用户的数据和
and session state from leaking
会话进行保护  以免它们
out with those requests.
随着这些请求而泄漏
When you provide your rule list
当你向 WebKit 提供规则列表时
to WebKit, WebKit compiles into
WebKit 会把它编译成
an efficient byte code format.
有效的字节码格式
This is kind of an
这是一种执行细节
implementation detail that's not
它与你并没有
directly relevant to you.
直接的关联
I'm bringing it up because I
我之所以提到它  是因为
want to assure you that a
我想向大家保证
content rule list even a large
无论是一个内容规则列表
set of thousands of rules we've
还是数千条规则形成的巨大集合
been spending a lot of time
我们都投入了大量时间精力
working on making that as
从而让事情
efficient as possible.
尽可能地高效运行
And no matter how big your rule
无论你的规则集
set is, if it compiles
有多么庞大 只要它编译成功
successfully you should not see
你就能看到
degradation in loading
它的加载性能
performance.
不会出现降低
You supply your rules in a
你用简单的 JSON 格式
simple JSON format.
来提供规则
The JSON has pairs of triggers
JSON 拥有好几对
and actions.
触发器和动作
In this example up on the
在大屏幕上的这个例子里
screen, the trigger is matching
这个触发器正在匹配
a url that is a url.
一个 URL 这是 URL
It's for every single url that's
对于每一个 URL 来说
a regular expression that says
这是一个正则表达式
for all urls take the action of
它表明所有 URL 都要执行
making the url https.
生成 URL HTTP 的动作
So this is a common and
所以说这是一个普通而又
important shotgun approach to
重要的一揽子解决办法
upgrading all plain text
它把所有的纯文本请求
requests to be encrypted ones.
升级为加密内容
I'm not going to go into the
我不打算在这里
other actions and triggers that
讨论其他现有的动作
are available right here because
和触发器  因为今天我
I have so much more I'd like to
想谈的事情还有很多
talk about today but there are
但我们会给大家
resources that we will refer you
介绍一些资源
to to get the full breadth of
以便全面获取
what is available to you.
你们可以得到的信息
Once you have your JSON, you'll
一旦你有了自己的 JSON 你要把它
pass it to the related new API,
传送给相关的新 API
WKContentRuleListStore, to
也就是 KContentRuleListStore
compile it into that efficient
从而把它编译成有效的
byte code format.
字节码格式
Now notice there's a string
现在请注意 有一个字符串
identifier passed in.
标识符传送进来了
It's up to you to come up with
现在要由你来决定
what the string is and it will
字符串的性质
be relevant in just a little
要不了多久  它就要
bit.
起作用了
You'll have a completion handler
你将获得一个 Completion Handler
and when your completion handler
当你通过 WKContentRuleList
is called with the
调用这个 Completion Handler时
WKContentRuleList, you can
就可以用那个已经安装的规则列表
create a WebView with that rule
来创建一个 WebView
list installed and start loading
并开始加载内容
content -- start loading web
--加载网页内容
content that filters out
它可以滤除
unwanted sub resources.
不需要的子资源
So that identifier.
标识符也是如此
When we compile a rule list from
当我们通过 JSON  把一个规则列表
JSON to the efficient byte code
编译为有效的字节码
format, you can name it.
格式时  你可以给它命名
And then later you can look up
然后你就可以使用
by the same identifier so you
同一标识符进行查找
don't have to compile it again.
这样你就不用再重新编译它
WebKit stores it on the storage
WebKit 把它存入设备的存储器
of the device and can look it up
这样它在以后就可以
much quicker later.
更快速地查找
So you can -- you only need to
所以你可以-- 你只需要
compile a certain rule set once.
把某个规则集编译一次就可以了
Once you have your
一旦你获得我刚才提到的
WKContentRuleList as I just
WKContentRuleList
mentioned, you add it to the
就把它添加到
WebView's configuration and now
WebView 配置中  那么现在
you're ready to go.
你马上就可以运行它了
I believe there's no better way
我相信  没有什么
to see what cool new APIs can do
比一场演示更能让你了解到全新API的
other than a demo.
炫酷功能
So I'd like to invite Alex on
所以我想邀请 Alex 上台
the stage to show you a little
为大家展示更多
bit more.
精彩
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
>> Thanks Brady.
>> 谢谢 Brady
I am making an app and it's an
我正在制作一款 App
educational app.
它是个教育类 App
And it will help people to learn
这款软件能使人们对
something more about a subject
某个主题有更多了解
that makes me very happy and
这个主题让我感到非常快乐
that is dogs.
就是狗
And so my users are going to
那么  我的用户是需要
read articles online.
在线阅读一些文章的
They're going to take a quiz on
他们要参加一个根据这些文章内容
these articles and then they are
而设定的测验 然后将会
going to receive a diploma.
获得一份证书
So since I am going to be
因为我准备
showing web content and
显示网页内容  还要把它们
integrating into my app, I'm
集成到我的 App 里面  所以我准备
going to use WKWebView.
使用 WKWebView
There we go.
马上开始
We have a very simple app that
我们现在有一个非常简单的 App
basically does nothing but open
基本上不用做别的 只需要打开
a WKWebView and open up the web
WKWebView  再在它里面打开
content in that WKWebView.
网页内容
Let's see what it looks like
让我们把它拿出来看看
right out of the box.
到底是什么样
Okay. So this web service checks
好了 这个 Web 服务检查了
the http header for the presence
当前这个 Http 页头的
of a cookie to indicate who the
一个 Cookie  以便显示
student is and if there is no
这名学生是谁 如果没有 Cookie  的话
cookie, then it will forward us
它会继续把我们引领到
to a log in screen.
一个登录界面
And we could click here to log
然后我们可以点击这里
in.
登录
And we could log in but this
我们可以登录 不过这项
user experience can be improved
用户体验还可以改进
upon and maybe we've already
或许我们已经
logged into the app using the
通过 Touch ID 或其他方式
touch ID or something.
登录 App 了
And we know how to communicate
我们知道如何利用这个
with this web service.
Web 服务进行交流
The fact that this student is
实际上  这位用户
logged in with a cookie.
是通过 Cookie 登录的
So we're going to do just that.
所以我们接下来就看一看这个
To do that, we need to make an
要想做到这一点 我们需要创建
http cookie.
一个 HTTP Cookie
We need to put this cookie into
我们需要将这个 Cookie
a website data store's
放入一个网址数据库的
httpCookieStore using the new
HTTPCookieStore  使用
API set cookie.
API 新创建的 Cookie
And then once that's done, we
一旦完成这一步  我们
need to tell the WKWebView to
就需要告诉 WKWebView
use the website data store that
让它使用包含这个 Cookie的
has the cookie inside of it and
网址数据库
we do so through the WKWebView
我们通过 WKWebView 的配置
configuration.
来完成这些
Right here.
就这样
Set the website data store to be
把这个网址数据库设置为
the one that has a cookie in it.
含有 Cookie 的网址数据库
And then we proceed as we did
然后我们按照前面的程序
before.
再做一遍
Use this configuration.
使用这个配置
Open a WebView.
打开一个 WebView
Open the web content.
打开网页内容
All right.
好了
So right off the bat, we are
我们立马登录
logged in.
成功
Our initial request has this
我们最初的请求在页头上
http cookie in its header.
是有这个 HTTP Cookie 的
So this article that I want my
所以  我想让用户读的这篇
users to read has some sub
文章里面有一些
resources that are loaded over
已加载到未加密
unencrypted http connections.
HTTP 链接的子资源
And our app transport security,
在默认状态下 我们这个 App的
by default, keeps our users safe
传输安全性通过阻止加载
by preventing loads over
未加密 HTTP 链接的方式  来保证
unencrypted http connections.
用户安全
And so right here, we see some
就在这个地方  我们看到了一些
missing images.
缺失的图像
These -- the servers from which
我们想要通过它们来
we wanted to get these images
获取这些图像的服务器
are correctly configured with
都已经成功配置了
https tls certificates on them
HTTP TLS 证书
and if we had made an encrypted
如果我们发出一个
https request, it would have
加密的 HTTP 请求
responded with the same image.
它会以同样的图像响应
So if we wanted to go in and
所以如果我们想要进入
take the http url and turn it
并且获得 HTTP URL
into an https url just before
然后把它变成
the load, then we would receive
一个尚未加载的 HTTP URL
the data that we wanted over a
然后我们就会通过一个安全链接
secure connection.
来接收原先想要的数据
Let's do that using a
让我们用 WKContentRuleList
WKContentRuleList.
来完成这件事
Okay. I added a little bit of
好了 我加了一点点
code.
代码
Here we have the content rule
这是我们想要使用的
list that we want to use.
内容规则列表
In this case we have one rule.
在这个案例里 我们有一条规则
It contains a trigger which is a
它包含一个触发器
regular expression that matches
这个触发器是一个正则表达式
everything.
能与一切相匹配
This regular expression is run
这个正则表达式是
on the urls of each resource
在 WebKit 准备从每个资源里抓取的
WebKit is about to fetch.
URL 上运行
The action is make https.
这项操作是创建 HTTPS
So if we would have requested an
因为我们如果已经发出请求
unsecure resource, request a
要获取的资源并不安全 那么基本上只需要
secure resource basically by
在方案里增加字母 s
just adding an s into the
就可以请求到安全的
scheme.
资源
Once we have this JSON, we need
一旦我们有了这个 JSON
to compile the content rule
我们就需要编辑内容规则
list.
列表
Once this content rule list is
在完成这个内容规则列表的
compiled, we need to take the
编辑之后　我们需要
content rule list and add it to
通过用户内容控制器
the WKWebView configuration
把这个内容规则列表添加到
through the user content
WKWebView 配置当中
controller and then proceed as
然后按照刚才的流程
before.
继续进行
So let's see what happens when
我们来看看这样做的话
we do this.
会发生什么
We load the article and these
我们加载这篇文章
resources are now being loaded
现在这些资源正通过安全连接
over secure connections.
而被加载
All right.
搞定
So we now have an app that
我们现在有一款 App
starts with cookies and it
它从 Cookie 着手
promotes all of its insecure
能够把所有的不安全资源
resources to secure resources.
升级为安全资源
Let's hear more about customized
现在我们有请 Brady
loading from Brady.
来详细介绍自定义加载方法
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
>> Thank you, Alex.
>> 谢谢你 Alex
Pretty straight forward.
非常直接清晰
I do want to reiterate a couple
我有两点想要重申
of points.
一下
Alex showed that you can now set
Alex 已经展示过了  大家现在可以
a cookie in a WKWebView and know
在 WKWebView 中设定一个 Cookie
when the right time is to make a
可以知道什么时候能够
request where that cookie will
使用 Cookie 来
be applied.
发送请求
And that's enabled by the new
通过 WKHTTPCookieStore API
WKHTTPCookieStore API.
就能够做到这一点
And then to hammer it home, the
我们继续把话说得更明白些
one little bit of the content
我们在这里要集中关注的
rule list power that we like
这个内容规则列表的
focusing on is upgrading
一项小功能
insecure, unencrypted resource
是仅仅通过这个简单的规则列表
requests to be https with just
将不安全、未加密的资源请求
that simple rule list.
升级为 HTTPS
With one action and one trigger.
只需要一步操作 一次触发
Alex showed how WebKit can
Alex 向大家展示了 WebKit
efficiently do that
如何自动帮助你
automatically on your behalf.
高效地完成这件事
And now I'd like to move on to
接下来我想介绍
our third and final new
我们的第三个  最后一个
mechanism which is the ability
新机制  那就是
to provide custom resources.
提供自定义资源的能力
We've heard from a lot of
我们从很多开发者
developers that they have a
那里了解到
bundle of web content that they
他们自己有一大堆网页内容
control.
要控制
Some of them put it in their
有些开发者把它放到了
application bundle.
App 程序套装里面
Some of them host it on a web
有些人把它托管在自己控制的
server that they control.
网络服务器上
And they would like to insert
他们想要把用户设备上的
into that web content resource
本地数据插入到
data local to the user's device.
网络内容资源里
One pretty cool app that has
有一款相当炫酷的 App
this need that we've seen is a
就有这种需求  我们见到过
photo book maker where it's
它是一个相册制作工具
using entirely web technologies
它完全凭借网络技术
to have a photo book layout
来获得相册版式
where the company's designers
公司的设计师
are adding new templates for new
不断把新模板加入到新的相册
layouts and styles of the photo
版式和风格设计里
books but they want to access
但是他们想要访问
photos that are local to the
用户设备上的
user's device.
本地图片
And using this new API that will
利用这款新的 API
be possible.
就可以实现了
There's also a lot of game
另外还有许多的
developers out there we hear
游戏开发者
from who have an in game
听他们说 他们有一个游戏内通知
newsletter or an in game
或游戏内积分排行榜
leaderboard that uses web
他们使用的就是
technology.
网络技术
And they want to integrate local
他们想整合用户
experiences from their user's
在本地设备上玩游戏的
local play of the game so their
本地体验
user feels more attached to the
这样他们的用户就会觉得自己
goings on in the game's
跟游戏世界的最新进展
universe.
更加息息相关
These are just a couple of
这些只是几个
examples.
例子
There's many more things of what
通过新的 WKURLSchemeHandler API
you can do with the new
你还可以去做
WKURLSchemeHandler API.
更多的事情
WKURLSchemeHandler allows your
WKURLSchemeHandler API 让你的
app to handle resource loads for
App 能够针对具体的URL方案
a particularly url scheme.
来处理资源加载
Now just so we're all on the
那么这样一来  我们大家都
same page.
达成一致了
What is an url scheme?
什么是 URL 方案？
These are examples of some urls
这些是我们可能见到过的
we've probably seen.
一些URL示例
And these are the schemes.
这些就是方案
Everything that comes before the
第一个冒号前面的全部
first colon.
内容
So referencing custom url
所以通过引用 WebKit 自身
schemes that WebKit doesn't
还没有处理的
already handle itself, you can
自定义 URL 方案  你可以
register a scheme handler to
注册一个方案句柄
handle resource loads to any
来处理任一资源的加载问题
resource that has a url matching
只要这项资源里的某个 URL 与你的方案
that scheme.
相匹配
In this example, we've
在这个例子中
arbitrarily chosen the scheme
我们随意选择了
local.
本地方案
Not a standard url scheme that
它并不是由 WebKit 自己处理的
WebKit handles itself.
标准 URL 方案
Not any part of any web standard
它根本不属于哪种网络标准
or anything like that.
或与之相似的东西
But one could conceivably see
但我们可以想象到
how it could become a web
在将来它将能够
standard in the future.
成为一种网络标准
It might become something WebKit
它可能会成为 WebKit
handles itself.
独自处理的某种东西
So we'd like to encourage the
因此我们愿意鼓励
best practice of future proofing
人们在将来进行彻底实践
your custom scheme by name
来证明你的自定义方案
spacing it with your company
用你的公司名称或 App 套装的名称
name or the app bundle name,
或类似的名称
something like that.
来完成空间命名
What is a WKURLSchemeHandler
WKURLSchemeHandler  究竟是
itself?
什么
It's a fairly simple protocol
它是一种相当简单的协议
that you implement with two
你可以用两种方式执行它
methods so you are told to start
你要么是被安排
loading a scheme task or stop
加载一项方案任务
loading one.
或是停止加载一项任务
We'll get into what the scheme
我们过一小会儿再来
task is in a little bit.
谈谈什么是方案任务
Once you've implemented the
一旦你执行协议
protocol, you will set the
你就会在 WebView 的设置上
scheme handler on the WebView's
设立方案处理程序
configuration and this is where
这就是你决定
you decide which url scheme you
要使用这个方案处理程序
want that scheme handler to
为哪个 URL 方案
handle custom loads for.
来处理自定义加载
You can use the same instance of
你可以在 App上 所有
your class for all the custom
自定义的 URL 方案中
url schemes in your app.
使用同类的实例
You can have a different class
你也可以为不同的 URL 方案
for different url schemes.
设定不同的类别
You can have different instances
所以 你可以将不同的实例
for all the different schemes or
用于所有不同的方案
have one shared instance for all
或将一个实例
the schemes.
分别用于所有的方案
It's up to you and your
这取决于你和
application's architecture.
你的 App 程序的架构
And then you create your WebView
接下来 你要创建自己的 Webview
and load some content in it.
并在里面加载一些内容
And any sub resource in that web
这个网页内容里的
content that references your
参考了你已注册的
custom url scheme that you
自定义 URL 方案
registered will call back into
的网页内容  它包含的任何子资源
the object that you registered
都会反向调用你拿
with the WKWebView.
WKWebView 注册的对象
And note that this includes even
要注意 这甚至包括
the top level html document
最高级别的 HTML 文件本身
itself, can be of the custom
它可能属于你先前注册的
scheme that you registered.
自定义方案
So what is that WKURLSchemeTask.
那么 WKURLSchemeTask 是什么？
Each task sent to your handler
每个发送到你处理程序的任务
represents a specific sub
都代表一个特定的
resource load.
子资源加载
The task contains the url
这个任务包含 URL
request object.
请求对象
This is the same information
这是要传递到
that would go out to an http
某个 HTTP 服务器的相同信息
server if this request was going
如果说  这个请求要
out onto the network.
传递到网络上的话
It includes a lot of little bits
它包含了很多与资源相关的
of data about the resource but
小片段数据资料
very importantly, the url
可是它们却非常重要 尤其是
itself.
URL 本身
And then the task has four
再往下看  这项任务
straight forward methods for you
提供了四个直接了当的方法
to communicate loading progress
要让你将加载进程
back to WebKit for this
传递给 WebKit
particular resource.
从而获取这一资源
Once you are given a task and
一旦你接收到某个任务
told to start loading for it,
并且按照要求开始为它进行加载
first thing you need to do is
你首先要做的
create a response.
是创建一个响应
Just like that url request
就像 URL 请求对象
object represents what would go
代表着传送到
to a server on the network, this
一台网络服务器上的信息那样
is the response that would come
这个响应是服务器将要
back from the server.
返回的内容
You need to manufacture that.
你需要对它进行加工
Very importantly, in the
非常重要的是 在这个响应里
response, you need to include
你需要包含
the mime type.
MIME 类型
For those of you not yet
对于在座的
intimately familiar with web
还不算非常熟悉
technologies this is kind of
网络技术的人来说
like the file type.
它有点像是文件类型
It's you telling WebKit how to
这是要由你来告诉 WebKit
interpret the resource.
如何解读资源
This is an HTML resource.
这是一个 HTML 资源
This is a JPEG image, etc. Once
这是一个 JPEG 图像等等
you have the response, you tell
一旦你获得响应
the task that the response was
就要向任务告知
received.
响应已收到
In this case, we have all of the
在这种情况下 我们的内存里
data for the response in memory
已经具备了响应回复所需要的
already.
所有数据
So we can immediately pass the
所以我们可以立刻将
data back to WebKit for the
数据传送到 WebKit  从而
task.
完成任务
And then we signal completion of
我们随后将示意 WebKit
the load to WebKit.
加载已完成
So WebKit isn't waiting for more
所以 WebKit 就不会再等待
data to come in.
更多数据了
Again, no better way to
还是那句话 最好的
illustrate other than to see it
展示方式就是观看
into action.
操作演示
So I'd like to invite Alex back
所以 我要邀请 Alex
on to stage.
回到台上
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
>> Thanks Brady.
>> 谢谢 Brady
So remember in my app, I'm going
大家还记得 在我的 App 里
to have my users read articles
是要让在线阅读文章的用户
online, take quizzes on those
再参加关于这些文章的测试
articles, and then receive a
然后他们会收到
diploma.
一张毕业证书
And I have a team of web
我有一个网络设计团队
designers who is constantly
他们经常能
coming up with beautiful diploma
想到很漂亮的证书
designs.
设计格式
And so I want the users of my
所以我希望我的 App 用户
app to go and fetch these new
能去我的服务器里
designs from my servers but I
获取这些新设计  但我又想
want each diploma to include a
让每张证书里都有
picture of the user's avatar and
用户自己的头像
I want that to be loaded locally
而且我希望这些头像能够从本地
on the user's device.
加载到用户的设备上
And so to do this custom local
所以 要在 WebKit 内部实现
loading within WebKit, I am
这种自定义本地加载
going to use a custom scheme.
我就要使用一个自定义方案
Now let me show you the source
现在我给向大家展示一下
of my diploma.
我的证书来源
Okay. So here I have some HTML.
好了 看这里  我有某个 HTML
And I have an image.
我还有一张图片
And its source has a url with a
它的来源是一个带有
custom scheme.
自定义方案的 URL
In this case, canine school dash
在这个例子里
avatar.
犬科动物—头像
And if I open this in a browser
如果我用浏览器或
or in a WKWebView the WKWebView
WKWebView 打开它
won't know what to do with this.
WKWebView 并不会知道该做什么
Let me show you what that looks
那么我向大家快速展示一下
like really quick.
这是怎么回事
Take the quiz.
参加测验
Dogs. Yes.
狗 是的
Okay. So here I have my
好了 这样我就有
beautiful diploma.
一份漂亮的证书了
And I have a missing image tag
我有一个缺失的图像标记
because WebKit tried to load a
因为 WebKit 试图加载含有
resource that had the school --
犬类——
that had the scheme canine
“犬科动物——头像”方案
school dash avatar and WebKit
的资源
doesn't know what to do with
而 WebKit 不知道该怎样
such a scheme.
处理这样的方案
So we can use the
所以 我们可以用
WKURLSchemeHandler to teach this
WKURLSchemeHandler 来教会
WKWebView what to do with such a
这个 WKWebView 怎样处理类似的
request.
请求
Okay. So I added a bit of code.
好了 我加了一些代码
I have an object, a class that
我有一个对象 一个用来执行
implements WKURLSchemeHandler
WKURLSchemeHandler 的分类
and there's a bit of code.
这儿还有一些代码
I'll get back to this in a
我马上就回来
second.
再说这个
But down here, in my WKWebView
不过  往下看这里  我想在我的 WKWebView
configuration, I need to call
配置里调用
the new method set
设定新方法的
URLSchemeHandler with an
URLSchemeHandler  这里面有
instance of my class that
我的一个分类实例
implements url,
它执行 URL
WKURLSchemeHandler and then I
WKURLSchemeHandler  然后我
need to tell WebKit what url
需要告诉 WebKit  这个分类要
scheme this class is going to
处理的请求
handle the requests of.
是属于哪个 URL 方案
In my class implementation,
我在分类执行时
implementing WKURLSchemeHandler
执行 WKURLSchemeHandler
means I have these two methods.
就意味着我有这样两种方法
Start and stop.
开始和结束
Start is called by the web
当针对这个方案
content when a request for this
的请求生成时
scheme is generated.
网页内容就会调用开始方法
So in this case, when the web
所以在这个例子中  当网页内容
content wants to load my image.
想要加载我的图像时
It's my job to respond to this
我就应该用这个 URL 方案任务
request using this url scheme
对这个请求做出
task.
响应
In my case, I'm going to pull up
在我的例子里  我会暂停
an image picker and allow the
一个图片选择器  并让读者
user to pick an image.
来选择一张图片
So I don't need to respond
所以我不需要马上
immediately.
响应
If the WKWebView calls my stop
如果在这个过程中 WKWebView 调用了
method while this happening,
我的停止方法
then it -- I shouldn't respond
那么  我就不该再
to that request anymore because
响应这个请求了
it was cancelled or something
因为它已经被取消
like that.
或其他什么原因
Down here once my image picker
在这里 只要图片选择器完成工作
is done, I will have my data.
我就会得到数据
In this case, I will JPEG encode
在这个例子中 我要把它编码为 JPEG
it.
格式
And I need to call these three
我需要调用这三种
methods.
方法
Did receive response.
响应已收到
Did receive data and did finish.
数据已接收 已完成
Did receive data is special.
数据已接收  比较特别
I can call it more than once as
我可以不止一次地调用数据
the data is generated or as its
因为数据是生成的 或因为它是接收到的
received or however I want to
或不管我是以什么方式提供的
provide this data.
这些数据
In this case, I'm only calling
在这里 我只准备调用它一次
it once because I have the
因为我自己有
entire data of the response, the
这个响应的全部数据
JPEG encoded image in one
在一个缓存区里使用 JPEG 格式编码的
buffer.
图像
So let's see what happens when I
我们来看看  当我执行这项操作时
have this implemented.
会发生什么情况
Okay. I'm already logged in
好了 我已经登录了
because I have the cookie.
因为我有 Cookie 记录
Everything is loaded securely.
所有都已安全加载
I take the quiz.
我来参加测验
Dogs. Yes.
狗 是的
Okay. So this image picker comes
好了 这个图片选择器出来了
up because this start method has
因为这种开始方法
been called.
已经被调用
I go into my camera roll and I
我进入我的相册
choose my avatar photo that I
选择我的头像照片
want to be in my web content.
我想让它呈现在我的网页内容里
And then because of calling
然后  因为在任务当中
those methods on the task, I now
调用了那些方法
have that data in my web
现在我的网页内容里已经包含
content.
这份数据了
So I now have an application
所以我现在拥有这样一个 App
that manages its cookies, that
它可以管理它的各种 Cookie
uses a content rule list to
使用内容规则列表
upgrade insecure requests, and
升级不安全的请求
that does custom loading through
可以通过 WKURLSchemeHandler
a WKURLSchemeHandler.
进行自定义加载
Back to Brady.
现在让 Brady 继续来讲
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
>> So to reiterate once again,
>> 再次重申一下
what we just saw, Alex show us
我们刚才看到了  Alex 用代码形式
in code.
给我们做了展示
He chose a future proof url
他选择的是即将推出的 Proof URL
scheme.
方案
A best practice that I want to
这是我想要强调的
reiterate a few times to make
一个最佳方案  我想多强调几次
sure you don't choose a scheme
以便确保你在将来
that might become some sort of
不会选择某种有可能
standardized schema in the
标准化的
future.
方案
And then he showed something I
接下来他又展示了某样东西
hadn't even explicitly mentioned
是我还没来得及明确提到的东西
which is that you can provide
也就是说  你可能给
the data for a task
某项任务
asynchronously.
异步提供数据
You might generate the data
你可以在本地
locally.
生成数据
You might have the user take a
你可以让用户即时
picture.
拍照
You might do your own networking
你可以创建自己的网络
to get the data.
来获取数据
However long it takes for you to
无论你耗费多长时间来
get the data you can provide it
获取数据  你都可以将它
back to WebKit asynchronously.
异步传送返回到 WebKit
So that is it for all the new
这就是我今天
stuff I have to talk you about
想要和大家分享的所有
today.
新事物
Today we went over
今天我们仔细讨论了
WKHTTPCookieStore, the new API
WKHTTPCookieStore  这个
for managing cookies in your
用来在你的 WKWebView 里管理 Cookie
WKWebViews.
的新 API
We talked about
我们讲了
WKContentRuleList, a fast and
WKContent 规则列表  这是一种快速
efficient way to filter unwanted
有效的方法 它可以从你的 WKWebViews 里滤除
content from your WKWebViews.
不想要的内容
And we talked about
我们还讨论了
WKURLSchemeHandler, a fantastic
WKURLSchemeHandler  一种
way for you to provide custom
可以让你把自定义资源
resources to web content no
添加到网页内容里的绝妙方法
matter where that web content
无论网络内容
comes from.
从何而来
I'd like to reiterate one more
我想再一次强调
time that we came up with these
我们之所以能想到这些
new APIs and worked hard on them
新的 API   并且努力进行研发
because of developer feedback
是因为我们获得了
that we've gotten from all of
在座所有开发者的
you.
反馈
And we'd like you to continue
我们希望大家继续
giving us your feedback so we
给我们反馈建议  这样我们
can gather it and come up with
就能聚到一起  创造出
the next great new features that
我们将来新版本 WKWebView 里
will exist in future versions of
能够呈现
WKWebView.
更多出色的功能
For more information, please
想要了解更多信息
visit the website for this
请访问这次会议的
session and there are some
网址  还有一些相关的
related sessions I'd encourage
会议  我建议大家
you to look into.
去了解一下
Tomorrow morning we're going to
明天早上我们将讨论
talk about some great new things
Safari View Controller 里的
in Safari View Controller.
某些非常优异的新功能
So if you are interested in
如果你有兴趣给自己的 App 增添一种
adding a powerful in app web
功能强大的应用内
browsing experience to your
网络浏览体验
application, please come see
请大家过来
that.
再看看
And we also have -- well some
自从我们首次推出
old talks about when we first
WKWebView 以来
introduced the WKWebView API.
我们一直都有些分享
And also when we introduced
我们推出那些适用于 Safari 的
those content blocking
内容禁止扩展后
extensions for Safari.
情况也是这样
That's where you can get a lot
大家从这里可以了解许多
of detail on the powerful rule
关于这套强大规则设置的细节
set that is available to you
你在使用 WKContentRuleList
using WKContentRuleList.
可以用到这些
Thanks for coming and I hope you
感谢大家的到来 希望大家在
have a great rest of WWDC.
接下来的 WWDC 会议里能够满载而归
[ Applause ]
[掌声]